<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Walker Randolph Smith]]></title><description><![CDATA[Walker Randolph Smith]]></description><link>http://www.walkerrandolphsmith.com</link><generator>metalsmith-feed</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 22:39:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.walkerrandolphsmith.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><author><![CDATA[Walker Randolph Smith]]></author><item><title><![CDATA[Add Bitbucket Aside to Octopress]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Adding public repositories hosted on Bitbucket to your blog is a great idea to showcase your projects.
Checking out how the Github aside works will help, as they are similar.
However, unlike Github, repository names on Bitbucket can have white space, but the URL to a repository is stripped of white space and every letter is converted to lowercase.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.walkerrandolphsmith.com/add-bitbucket-aside-to-octopress</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.walkerrandolphsmith.com/add-bitbucket-aside-to-octopress</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Walker Randolph Smith]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VersionOne JavaScript SDK]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Recently the VersionOne JavaScript SDK received some love and got a major version release.
The SDK allows communication with a VersionOne instance by exposing some of the well documented apis including
 <code>query.v1</code>, <code>rest-1.v1</code>, and <code>metav1</code>. The SDK ultimately makes HTTP requests to a specified VersionOne instance.
In this scenario I will not consider CORS and make all the requests from a server.
This article assumes prior knowledge around Node.js and javascript.
I will cover how to set up a minimal node application that uses an express server and the SDK to make queries to VersionOne.
You can follow along with this git repo <a href="https://github.com/walkerrandolphsmith/sample-v1sdk-app">sample-v1sdk-app</a>.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.walkerrandolphsmith.com/versionone-javascript-sdk</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.walkerrandolphsmith.com/versionone-javascript-sdk</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Walker Randolph Smith]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Electron Native Apps]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Electron allows for creating cross platform, native applications that run on the Node.js runtime.
Today, native applications can be created with a consistent set of tools including Javascript, HTML, and CSS.
Electron, developed by Github, was orginally known as Atom Shell as it powered the homegrown text editor created at Github, Atom.
Now well known applications such as Slack, Atom, Visual Studio Code, and more have been developed with Electron.
I am going to cover creating a minimal Electron application.</p>]]></description><link>http://www.walkerrandolphsmith.com/electron-native-apps</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.walkerrandolphsmith.com/electron-native-apps</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Walker Randolph Smith]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>